ambitiouskitchen.com 2019-04-23

# Privacy Policy | Ambitious Kitchen

_Effective as of May 24, 2018_

By accessing and browsing this Website, you agree to be bound by these Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. In the event of any violation of these Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, or any applicable laws, we intend to fully cooperate with any law enforcement officials or agencies in the investigation of such violations.

This policy may change without notice. You should periodically check this page to stay up to date with the latest policy. This policy is effective May 24, 2018. While these practices may be changed, any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, rather than a retroactive basis. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

## **No warranty**

AMBITIOUS KITCHEN DOES NOT MAKE ANY WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND.

The Website is provided on an “as is” and “as available” basis. Ambitious Kitchen disclaims all warranties, express and implied, including but not limited to fitness for a particular purpose, merchantability, non-infringement, availability, or security.

We make a reasonable effort to provide accurate information, but cannot warrant that any information provided is accurate, complete, reliable, or current. We provide no warranty or assume liability for any information on the Website.

## **What information do we collect?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: 

  * To personalize your experience: your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
  * To improve our website: we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To send periodic emails.
  * The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form, enter information on our site, or simply browsing the site.

We may collect personal information from you that you’ve voluntarily submitted to us, such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to this website when signing up for newsletters or submitting a comment or submitting an inquiry via our contact form.

We may also collect anonymous information such as your IP address. Anonymous information consists of non-personally-identifiable data. For example, when you use our website, we can log your IP address, the device you are using, operating system, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, time spent on our site, when you came to our site. We may also collect information on actions you take while visiting our website, such as what links or buttons you clicked on.

## **Do we use cookies?**

Yes. Cookies are files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information

We use cookies to keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction, such as browser type & operating system, tracking the number of visitors to this site, and a visitor’s demographics, so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

Cookies also help us to understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved user-experience.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies through your browser settings. Look at your browser’s Help Menu to modify your cookies.

You have the option of subscribing to our newsletter. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel embedded in emails allows an analysis of the success of our email marketing campaign. These tracking pixels allow us to see when you opened the email, if you opened the email, and what links you clicked in the email. This also allows the website to adapt future newsletter content to the interest of the user. This behavior is strictly confidential and will not be passed onto third parties.

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting is in use on this website. Collected aggregate data (such as age, gender and interests) is used to guide content in order to better serve visitors. It may also be cited in media kits and referenced in discussion with potential partnerships.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including our website. Some features of this website may cease to be available to you.

## **Interest-Based Advertising**

_Advertising Privacy Statement_

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

_For European Economic Area Residents_

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

## **Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

Some of our advertisers may use technology such as cookies when they advertise on our site. The advertiser’s technology can send these advertisers information that may be contained in log files. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing Florida rental houses to someone who has been looking up airfare for Florida, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing home decor ads to someone who frequents home decor sites).

## **Rights to your information**

**_Email Addresses_**

Opt-out: you may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe link in all our emails. You may also email us at monique@ambitouskitchen.com to be removed from our mailing list at any time.

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, leave a comment, or enter a promotion. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us. You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of the email.

Your email address may also be shared with the technology provider we use in connection with the purposes for which you provided it. For example, we use Mailchimp to deliver our email newsletters. Information provided is transferred to Mailchimp for processing in accordance to their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/).

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

## **Comment, Registration or Account Data**

As you use the Site, we collect other data that you provide voluntarily. For example, if you leave a comment, the Site will record your name as provided. You are welcome to use a nick-name instead, if you would rather not have your name published in conjunction with the comment.

We may also collect information about you through other voluntary methods, including research surveys.

We may use your personally-identifying information for a variety of our internal business purposes, such as creating a better user experience for the Site, diagnosing and troubleshooting malfunctions on the Site, better understanding how the Site is used, and making personalized recommendations to you.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

## **Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i) access your personal data

(ii) ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v) the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us addressed to the following:

monique@ambitiouskitchen.com

## Children Under the Age of 13

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Website or on or through any of its features/register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of this Website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or  
about a child under 13, please contact us at monique@ambitiouskitchen.com

## **Nutrition Information**

Ambitious Kitchen provides approximate nutrition information for convenience and as a courtesy only. Nutrition data is gathered primarily from the USDA Food Composition Database, whenever available, or otherwise other online calculators. Nutrition information can vary for a recipe based on precision of measurements, brands or the source of nutrition data. We strive to keep the information as accurate as possible, but make no warranties regarding its accuracy and encourage readers to make their own calculations.

The authors of the Website are not dietitians or nutritionists. Any recommendations are made based on our research or personal experience, but shall not be construed as medical or nutritional advice. You are fully responsible for any actions you take and any consequences that occur as a result of anything you read on this Website.

The Website or content herein is not intended to cure, prevent, diagnose or treat any disease. Please consult your health care provider regarding any health related decisions.

Ambitious Kitchen, Inc nor Monique Volz shall not be liable for adverse reactions or any other outcome resulting from the use of recipes or recommendations on the Website or actions you take as a result.

## Exercise and Workout Disclaimer

This site offers health, fitness and nutritional information and is designed for educational purposes only. You should not rely on this information as a substitute for, nor does it replace, professional medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. If you have any concerns or questions about your health, you should always consult with a physician or other health-care professional. Do not disregard, avoid or delay obtaining medical or health related advice from your health-care professional because of something you may have read on this site. The use of any information provided on this site is solely at your own risk.

Whether you have experienced health issues or you are extremely fit, you should always consult your physician or other health care professional before starting any fitness program promoting on our site or any fitness routine we have outlined, to determine if it is right for your needs. Do not start this fitness program if your physician or health care provider advises against it. If you experience faintness, dizziness, pain or shortness of breath at any time while exercising you should stop immediately.

Developments in medical research may impact the health, fitness and nutritional advice that appears here. No assurance can be given that the advice contained in this site will always include the most recent findings or developments with respect to the particular material. If you are in the United States and think you are having a medical or health emergency, call your health care professional, or 911, immediately.

## **Copyright**

This website, including all images, text, software, and other content is the property of Ambitious Kitchen, and is protected by United States and international copyright laws. All rights reserved.

You may have the opportunity to download ebooks or other digital products from our Website or newsletter. If you decide to do this, we grant you a limited, non-exclusive, personal, non-transferable license to use the product(s). You agree that you are not allowed to modify, distribute, sell, share, republish, or create derivative content from any information provided to you without express consent from Ambitious Kitchen.

You have our permission to use a link to our Website from your website. You may use one photo or excerpt (up to 100 words) from any post, with a mandatory link back to the post on our Website where it originated. We do not allow re-posting an entire recipe or more than one paragraph of a post, using photos without linking back, or presenting any of our content as your own. Any distribution of content from Ambitious Kitchen beyond what is described herein constitutes copyright infringement.

You may view and print any content displayed on the Website for personal, non-commercial use, provided that all copyright and attribution notices remain intact. You agree not to reproduce, publish, transmit, distribute, sell, license, modify, or create derivative content from this Website or any part of it, without prior written consent from Ambitious Kitchen.

## **Advertisements and third party links**

We use third party service providers on AmbitiousKitchen.com to support our site. These advertisements pay for the costs of running a large website and support the content that we provide to you for free.

Display Ads: we may use a third-party vendor to serve content and advertisements on our website, which may use cookies, as noted above. The use of cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet.

Retargeting Ads: from time to time, we may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies like Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the website. You can find out more about their usage of cookies by locating their privacy policy.

## **Affiliate programs**

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to [**Amazon.com**](https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2FAmazon.com%2F&h=ATMnTKBCQpe5oFbNYFNVlZKeitIxWMuiO0d4zpPYzpL98uw66P6kBSlsmjKI0EP37Bc3wH51Npa8isbuf6wYUmcJtijtoLuaPtUYoU_EhfeUKZC8oOAPz3n6n7yKUJDmkiJ07ZizxB5xPQ) and affiliated sites. As part of this program, Ambitious Kitchen can post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their websites. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

We are a participant of the rewardStyle Affiliate program. rewardStyle is a platform designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to various retail brands and affiliated sites. As part of this program, Ambitious Kitchen can post customized links, provided by rewardStyle, to track the referrals to their websites. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

On occasion, Ambitious Kitchen will participate in other non-specified affiliate programs, which have the capability to track the referrals to their websites and utilize cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

## **Sponsored Content**

We occasionally get opportunities to work with companies by creating a recipe using a specific product, hosting a giveaway, or very rarely reviewing a product. A disclosure will _always_ be included at the top of every sponsored post. Even when we are compensated, we will be 100% honest in our opinions. We will only share products that we believe in and are a good fit for Ambitious Kitchen and for the Ambitious Kitchen audience. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

## **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Site, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using our Site or services after the Effective Date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.

## **Contact us**

If there are any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at monique@ambitouskitchen.com.
